attachment attachment catchment style
what is the key to a happy relationship
in the book attached the authors argue
that the secret is understanding
attachment styles but what are
attachment styles in the first place how
can we use this to find an amazing
relationship or improve the ones that we
already have in today's video i break
down the book attach in just 20 minutes
and some of the things that we're going
to talk about in this video are what are
secure and insecure attachment styles
why they matter how attachment styles
affect our needs in a relationship how
to resolve problems and handle conflict
with attachment cells the most dangerous
and capable attachment partnership and
when to end the relationship but most of
all you'll learn how to adopt the
behaviors of the secure attachment cell
and use it to make your relationships
not only more fulfilling but actually be
happy in your relationship in a
practical way before we start please
support the authors dr amir levine and
rachel heller by purchasing their book
and quick shout out to short form for
helping me prepare for this video but
first
this is me
i grew up in the asian household i had
to figure out a lot of things on my own
like dating fast forward to my mid-30s
i was going through breakup after
breakup not knowing why sometimes i
would feel so anxious that my partner
would leave me other times i felt so
suffocated and just want to be alone but
was until my friend athena recommended
this book attached where i wasn't as
crazy as i thought it was maybe it was
because i was completely unaware of my
attachment style but what is an
attachment style in the first place
[Music]
if there was one thing you could learn
that would give you the opportunity to
create a deep amazing fulfilling and
secure romantic relationship it would be
learning your attachment style and about
the attachment system
so if you ever dated then you probably
experience asking yourself why did this
person suddenly ghost me or why is this
person so damn clingy well i like to
believe that my date suddenly decided to
go on a silent retreat after our first
date or that i'm such an awesome person
and be around that this person feels the
need to call and text me all the time
more likely reason is probably something
called attachment theory everyone has an
attachment system or mechanism in your
brain which helps you find monitor and
maintain intimacy with the chosen
partner think of it as an internal
matchmaker that lives in our brain it's
part of our evolutionary adaptation
which helped us develop close bonds with
others however everyone responds a bit
differently to closeness sometimes it's
due to dating experiences or our
relationships with our caregivers
growing up some people suppress intimacy
others embrace it and this was the
development of attachment cells these
are the beliefs and behaviors that
determine how we function in intimate
relationships and there are three main
styles secure attachers who are
nurturing responsive and comfortable
with intimacy anxious attachers who are
also known as anxious preoccupied who
constantly seek reassurance from their
partner and avoiding attachers also
known as dismissive avoidant who are
more distant and see intimacy as a
threat to their independence but okay
maybe you take a test maybe actually
figure out your attachment style so why
does this actually matter let's talk
about it
how can i be certain i'm making the
right choice you don't know the only way
you will know is by being with that
person by exchanging by discovering by
communicating by exploring by asking
questions by meeting you'll feel much
more relaxed if you allow yourself that
uncertainty that curiosity that openness
rather than trying to to know right away
finding an emotionally satisfying
romantic relationship actually helps us
become more independent but how does
relying on someone make you more
independent and that's the paradox
especially in the world of online dating
apps and hookup culture sometimes we
underestimate the power of feeling safe
long-term relationships that's our
safety net when we fall our partners
catch us we can feel a sense of security
comfort love and we actually feel more
encouraged to become independent bold
and brave but what happens when our
partners don't give us the emotional
support that our brains crave for we ask
for it we demand it or even fight for it
sometimes we seek it out at all costs
and when our emotional needs aren't met
arguments erupt relationships start to
deteriorate and since we don't feel safe
in those moments of change we lack the
courage to be our best selves and thrive
from a neuroscience point of view this
can trigger our survival state it can
activate our amygdala which turns off
empathy critical thinking and emotional
regulation all these things are probably
really important for a relationship this
is where attachment styles come into
play they help us understand both our
own and our partner's needs if you can
decipher others attachment styles you'll
be able to assess whether a potential
partner is actually capable of
fulfilling those needs and if you're
already with a partner you'll finally
understand
what lies at the root of your conflicts
and how to resolve them that is where
the three main attachment styles secure
anxious and avoidant come into play let
me explain secure attachment these
people have a desire for intimacy but
are also comfortable with emotional
distance by default secure attachers
assume that their partners love them and
don't worry about their relationships
falling apart spontaneously they are
good at communicating their emotional
needs and can keep their emotions steady
when faced with adversity and most of
all secure attachment styles tend to
have happier relationships compared to
insecure attachment styles so if you're
in a relationship with a secure attacher
you feel emotionally safe being with
them makes it easier for you to face the
outside world dating a secure attacher
tends to make insecure attachers more
secure but what happens when you're
secure yourself your relationship goal
is to maintain your secure attachment
style you're good at recognizing cues
that indicate compatibility so you tend
not to get trapped in negative
relationships but on the other hand you
may let negative behaviors repeatedly
slide in and sometimes you might stay in
a relationship longer than you should if
you start to recognize the anxious or
avoiding tendencies it might be time to
actually leave your relationship anxious
attachment anxious detachers have a
desire for intimacy with a romantic
partner but are hyper-sensitive to any
threats that endanger the relationship
while they might not say it at the
conscious level anxious detachers tend
to believe that their survival depends
on the success of their partnership it
feels like life and death so they tend
to stay on guard and when they do
perceive a threat they're flooded with
activating strategies so that they can
save the relationship like constantly
texting it's only until that intimacy is
re-established where the anxious
attacher kind of relaxes a little bit
but that protest behavior can cause harm
in the relationship and if you're an
anxious attacher yourself accepting your
romantic needs is the key to developing
a happy relationship way too often
anxious attachers try to ignore their
needs for intimacy or reassurance
because they feel ashamed of them but
this is the exact opposite that most
experts recommend to do if you don't
accept these needs you'll never give the
opportunity for your partners to fulfill
them and sometimes anxious attachers may
select a partner who's incapable of
fulfilling these needs regardless of the
reason anxious attachers tend to
perpetually be unhappy because the
relationship isn't giving or fulfilling
their needs avoid an attachment avoidant
attachers don't have that same desire to
get as close with their romantic
partners but like everyone they still
seek an intimate connection but what
happens when the partnership gets too
close they feel suffocated and
oftentimes this not only affects their
romantic relationships but parenting too
experts say avoidant attachers may not
enjoy parenting as much as secure
attachers because they tend to find
parenting more stressful and if you're
an avoidant attacher like myself
recognizing and combating your thoughts
and actions can help you have a happy
relationship one strategy that is
recommended is to second-guess negative
thoughts about your partner simply
asking is this really a problem or am i
trying to push my partner away if the
thing you dislike about your partner
isn't really a problem but still bothers
you maybe it's time to make an attempt
to accept your partner's flaws one of
the ways to do this is to keep
perspective of our own flaws which may
allow us to empathize with our partner
but okay we understand the three
different types of attachment styles but
which attachment style combination
should he absolutely avoid and what can
we learn from it well let me explain
what is bickering bickering is low
intensity chronic warfare it's this
notion that every time one person says
something the other person has a
reaction to it it's like you've got this
proximity it's like celex you know and
it constantly is friction friction but
it is constantly negative friction
anxious avoidant partnerships are the
relationship
death spiral the attacher wants to be
closer sometimes avoid an attacher will
fulfill the needs for increased intimacy
with their partner but over time the
avoidant attacher becomes uncomfortable
and starts to withdraw this is why we
see ghosting sometimes and when we see
the avoidant attacher start to pull away
the anxious attacher responses by
reconnecting even more which then causes
the avoidant partner to withdraw even
more while these partners may love each
other their interactions tend to worsen
over time in the long term they get
stuck in a continuous cycle of conflict
with the tension of their needs unmet
constantly clashing the relationship
eventually ends and most experts they
recommend to avoid this combination at
all costs anxious attachers should avoid
long-term relationships with avoidant
attachers who can't meet their intimacy
needs avoidant attackers should steer
clear of anxious attachers who will
exacerbate their desire for independence
but what happens if you're already in
this relationship dynamic does it mean
you got to break up not exactly
[Music]
how you heal this stuff is to learn how
do i stand still it's not just an
intellectual thing you need to learn and
understand the intellectual but to
actually transform it requires a
changing of your internal dialogue so if
you're already in a anxious avoidant
partnership what should you do one way
is that you can find a secure role model
by behaving like a secure person this
insecure attacher can gradually develop
a more secure attachment style over time
the more secure the relationship tends
to be the more fulfilling it is as well
so how do you actually practice secure
behavior effectively both partners
should do the following three step one
find a role model who has a comfortable
and secure way of dealing with others
step two practically think about what
would they do how would they act in
these life situations
and when you do inevitably face conflict
step number three think about what your
role model would do in the moment and
use their behavior to inform your own
while modeling a secure attacher is
helpful conflict will inevitably come up
so how do you actually manage this well
let's talk about that
all relationships are colored with
expectations we create the others in
relationships and in communication it
isn't just that's who they are and
that's who we are that is one of the
most important things to understand
about relationships and communication is
how people actually co-create each other
in the context of a relationship and why
we are not the same person with
different people because those people
make part of who we are how to behave
more securely in your relationships
whether we're single partnered up or
booed up learning to communicate like a
secure attacher helps us thrive in
intimate relationships if you're seeking
a new partner communicating your needs
directly and honestly can help us choose
someone who's actually emotionally
capable of meeting them and weed out the
ones who can't fulfill our needs but how
do you actually handle conflicts like a
secure attacher the goal is to express
our needs and expectations directly in a
non-threatening inoffensive and
non-critical manner and there's five
rules for communicating this like a
secure attacher rule one be honest and
speak openly remember your needs matter
no matter how your partner feels about
them while it might be scary it's only
making your desires clear giving your
partner the chance and opportunity to
fulfill your needs rule number two
express your needs directly without
blaming or judging oftentimes we can use
phrases like i need i feel and i want
remember your goal is not to make your
partner feel inadequate after all their
needs are just as valid as yours rule
number three use i statements to
actually discuss your personal
experience sometimes people will use i
feel statements to blame the other
partner common examples i feel like
you're unkind but these statements
actually hurt the discussion this is
about communicating your needs not your
partner's actions rule number four use
specific examples to communicate your
concerns especially in the beginning of
the conversation these are great for
setting the tone of the conversation
don't rely on generalities don't allow
the opportunity for your partner to be
like what do you mean this leaves room
for misunderstanding so stick to
concrete language rule number five and
this is the one i always ignored in high
school and college time your discussion
for when both parties are calm and
collected if the situation is already
volatile let it simmer down both people
can't be in a survival state to have an
open and honest discussion most people
need to be in a relaxed setting to
activate their prefrontal cortex which
is responsible for things like empathy
emotional regulation and critical
thinking things you probably want in
conversation like this but what happens
when your partner brings something to
you when they're upset or emotionally
charged how do you defuse it and how do
you resolve this situation tactfully
just listen to the difference i'm always
the one who does the dishes you never do
the dishes when's the last time that you
ever put the plate in this in the sink
let alone in the dishwasher okay
now you know what i had a really long
day and i'm exhausted
can you do the dishes tonight do you
hear the difference and do you hear
which one is more likely to get you the
thing that you're asking for even the
most secure couples fight about basic
daily life issues but these arguments
can actually help couples grow closer
why this is because secure attachers
follow certain rules of communication
that allow them to work through the
conflict without destroying their
relationship in the process these are
the following rules to actually work
through it rule number one prioritize
both you and your partner's happiness
this is a partnership the goal of every
conflict is to end in a win-win
situation so before starting the
conversation set the tone align with the
shared purpose you can demonstrate that
you care about them by laying out the
facts expressing your feelings and then
asking your partner's perspective from
there rule number two keep the argument
centered on the present issue sometimes
in the hedo moment it's easy to get
sidetracked or explain the argument to
include other issues so typically a
conflict about leaving the kitchen a
mess shouldn't turn into argument about
who takes on more work in the household
but this is easier said than not so
something comes up during the
conversation that needs to be dealt with
it's recommended to schedule a separate
conversation at a later time to discuss
it rule number three stay focused and
don't distance yourself emotionally or
physically oftentimes we need to
approach the issue head-on until it gets
resolved in a mutually agreeable way at
times it's easy to feel threatened in
the conversation which can trigger a
flight response but focusing on the best
intentions for both partners can help
with the flight response as well step
number four tell your partner exactly
what you need and what no matter how
long you've been with a partner they
can't anticipate all your needs telling
your partner exactly what you want may
also prevent miscommunication consider
active listening before responding to
your partner you can repeat back what
you think they said to help validate
them ensure that you're listening to
them and understood their message
correctly my favorite technique it's
labeling from never split the difference
it uses sensory language like it sounds
like it seems like it looks like it
feels like but what happens when you try
all these things and you realize maybe
this really isn't worth the effort so
when should you end the
relationship
when we say how do we get how do i get
over someone we're really saying like i
want to forget them and i'll be when i
finally don't think about them and have
no feelings for them then i'll be done
with it but we never really forget
people right and we shouldn't because so
it's more about finding what is the
wisdom in the experience relationships
aren't always cut clear and dry they're
messy and not all relationships can be
fixed if your partnership has become
harmful and possibly abusive then you
may need to end it here are some of the
signs according to the authors of when
to end a relationship number one your
partner is kind to everybody else but
not to you in fact it's so bad that you
don't even want to discuss with others
about how your partner treats you number
two your partner values other opinions
more than yours number three you don't
really know much about your partner's
life so you feel like you have to spy on
them and find out number four you don't
know if you can counter your partner to
be there in case of emergency situation
while these aren't absolute truths our
feelings along with this objective view
on relationships can help us make the
difficult decision to end the
relationship but now that you know these
attachment styles you're probably
wondering can i actually become a secure
attacher and so here's what i've
experienced by doing that if you want to
change the other change yourself if you
change one part and consistently
non-contingently hold on to it sooner or
later the other one has to adapt they
say it takes about four years to make a
complete shift from an insecure
attachment style to secured and since my
last breakup about a little over a year
ago i stayed single to really work on
myself specifically going from avoidant
attachment style to secure when i've
implemented these steps for myself
personally i found that i'm able to
communicate my needs better recognize my
default patterns and understand the
people around me for the better this has
not only helped me with my romantic life
but also my
platonic and business relationships too
instead of constantly obsessing about my
shortcomings i'm able to see the
external factors around me affecting the
relationship dynamics as someone who's
of avoiding attachment i had to rely on
myself for a lot of my needs growing up
trusting people is really scary and new
for me especially when i've been cheated
on in the past and abandoned by my
closest relationships communicating my
needs is something new because my asian
family dynamic was so volatile growing
up sometimes it's really hard like
really hard to have these discussions
and as i i was learning about this
sometimes i wonder
what could have happened if i actually
knew about this earlier but this book
attached it gave me the hope that i can
change and i hope it'll do the same for
you that is attached broken down and
here are some other videos that you'll
probably like stay compassionate stay
authentic stay rebellious peace